<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get Started on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/</link><description>Recent content in Get Started on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/introduction/</guid><description>No matter if you are a beginner programmer or if you&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for years, this guide will provide resources for all levels of expertise. If there is something that you already know in the specialization roadmaps that I have here, feel free to skip the material or use it as an opportunity to review what you already know and potentially fill in some gaps in your understanding.
Blockchain development might seem very intimidating at first, there are many moving parts, foundational knowledge from various different fields is required, the technologies are constantly evolving and aren&amp;rsquo;t as mature as in other areas of development such as in the web development space, there is a financial aspect to almost every application as you are programming on top of a value layer, etc.</description></item><item><title>General foundation</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/general-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/general-foundation/</guid><description>In order to get started with blockchain development on Ethereum, one must first get started with understanding how blockchains work in order to build a mental model of how each moving piece works and to get an understanding of the design principles which will govern your development experience.</description></item><item><title>Blockchains</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/blockchains/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/blockchains/</guid><description>The term blockchain has two different meanings, it can either relate to a data structure or to a computer network.
A blockchain (data structure) consists of sets of transactions or data bundled inside a container where each container has a cryptographic hash of the data in the previous container (block) within it. If the contents of the previous block change, the hash changes as well and thanks to this feature we can assure that the data hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tampered with.</description></item><item><title>Ethereum</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/ethereum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/ethereum/</guid><description>Since this is a guide about blockchain development on Ethereum, it is required to know how the Ethereum blockchain works, and the changes that it will undergo in the future so as to be prepared for what&amp;rsquo;s to come as a developer. If you have done web development before you can think of changes as a new ECMAScript standard, a new browser compile target (ie. WASM), a new engine (V8), etc&amp;hellip; The Ethereum blockchain is constantly evolving and quite a few changes will be put in place in the future before the core technologies of the network will start to ossify.</description></item><item><title>Smart contracts</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/smart-contracts/</guid><description>A smart contract is a program that runs on the Ethereum blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s a piece of code that has functions and data (state) which resides at a specific address on the Ethereum blockchain.
Smart contracts are a type of Ethereum account meaning that they have a balance and can send transactions over the network. They are deployed on the network and run as programmed, user accounts (externally-owned accounts, or EOAs) can interact with a smart contract by submitting transactions that interact with functions that are publicly accessible.</description></item><item><title>Web 2.0</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/web2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/web2/</guid><description>Although blockchain developers build decentralized applications, the technologies used to build these applications overlap to a big extent. User interfaces for Dapps are hosted on the internet and are built with traditional web technologies. In order to interact with a smart contract, a user needs to submit a request to a server that hosts an application and that application needs to create a transaction, get the signature from a user via a web3 wallet like Metamask, and then submit the transaction to an Ethereum RPC.</description></item><item><title>What makes decentralization important?</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/decentralization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/decentralization/</guid><description>In the web 2.0 world, we&amp;rsquo;re used to have a main account on platforms like Google and Facebook which we use to log into other services. All of our data is hosted inside of centralized databases and our private information is used in advertising software to sell us products. In exchange for our data, we get free services. These big centralized entities have a lot of power and control over our daily lives through the products we use each and every day.</description></item><item><title>Web3 values</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/web3-values/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/web3-values/</guid><description>The web3 movement is one about creating a value layer for the internet where we can setup incentive structures for the betterment of society in order to make a fairer world where access to products and services is openly distributed, permissionless and accessible to everyone on the planet no matter their provenance.
There are many good initiatives like Kernel, Gitcoin, GreenPill and many others that try to help educate about and fund the new wave of public goods and inrastructure in order to create a better world.</description></item><item><title>Play around</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/play-around/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/play-around/</guid><description>Blockchain development might feel overwhelming, and frankly very intimidating when you are starting out. To remedy this feeling, I suggest you look at programming on blockchains like an adventure game. You can explore what is possible, experiment by creating small projects with technologies that you find interesting, looking at what other people are building and interacting with their applications, debate with various people about their favorite applications, technologies and get a feel for how everything works.</description></item><item><title>Connect</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/get-started/connect/</guid><description>Blockchain development is a fairly new field and so most information about how to build applications in web3 is available on the internet and not in universities and other educational institutions. This might make it a lonely endeavor, but it need not be! There are people all across the world learning how to build cool projects with these technologies and everyone is looking to learn from each other and make friends in the space.</description></item></channel></rss>