<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Core development on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/</link><description>Recent content in Core development on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/introduction/</guid><description>This section was made possible thanks to @protolambda, he&amp;rsquo;s an Ethereum researcher and core dev who previously worked at the Ethereum foundation who now works for the Optimism Ethereum L2.
Thank you very much Proto for contributing your knowledge!</description></item><item><title>General learning</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/general-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/general-learning/</guid><description>There are many topics to learn about in core-development, one can specialize in any area. Here is a selection of learning-resources:
Basic # Merkle trees: Ethereum execution-layer Merkle Patricia Tree walkthrough Execution and Consensus layer Merge design, video by Danny Ryan Rollup centric roadmap, post by Vitalik Ethereum protocol ELI5 (coming soon) Medium: # Yellow Paper: L1 protocol specification in paper form ABI: Application Binary Interface to interact with contracts EVM opcodes: interactive reference RLP: the encoding used everywhere in execution-layer SSZ specs: encoding and merkleization of Eth2, also see visualized encoding and visualized hash-tree-root.</description></item><item><title>Layer 2</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l2/</guid><description>Layer-2 scales Layer-1 by increasing capacity without significantly changing the security assumptions of the Layer-2. Although this does not change L1 itself, it does influence the general scaling design direction, generally pushing ethereum into a rollup-centric roadmap.
Domains: # Side-chains: EthHub, eth org State channels: EthHub, eth org Plasma (mostly deprecated): EthHub, eth org Rollups intro by Polynya ZK rollups (ZKRUs): EthHub, eth org Optimistic rollups (ORUs): EthHub, eth org Bridges: eth org intro L3 / validiums / volitations etc: starkware L3 Validium eth org intro Refer to L2beat.</description></item><item><title>Layer 1</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l1/</guid><description>Domains: # Eth1 / execution layer Networking: devp2p EVM Tx pool Sync methods (Fast, Snap, Archive, Beam, Light) State DB User-facing (JSON RPC, tx tracing, etc.) Eth2 / consensus layer Networking: libp2p Fork-choice Attestations / BLS aggregation Staking / Validator clients Slashings Sharding</description></item><item><title>News</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/news/</guid><description>Selection of protocol news resources: # Week in Ethereum: OG weekly news letter Eth2.News: eth2 news by Ben Edgington harding Ethereum cat herders: Channel discussing changes in core dev calls and EIP specifications Ethereum foundation: YouTube channel where Ethereum core dev calls are hosted after they are done Ethereum/pm: This repository is used for project management for various initiatives affecting the Ethereum protocol. The main use of this repository is for the All Core Devs meeting, but it is also used for Ethereum 1.</description></item><item><title>Communications</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/communication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/communication/</guid><description>Most relevant communication channels # Discord Eth R&amp;amp;D server Eth magicians, forum for governance / protocol discussion Eth research, forum for research discussion AllCoreDevs (ACD): discord channel in R&amp;amp;D Ethereum Foundation youtube channel (streams ACD and Consensus calls)</description></item><item><title>Ethereum core teams</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/core-teams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/core-teams/</guid><description>Eth1 - execution layer Eth2 - consensus layer (nomenclature recently depreciated, but still used in some contexts)
Client teams (those that are open-source), in no particular order:
Domain Project Language Discord Docs Eth2 Prysm Go invite docs Eth2 Lighthouse Rust invite docs Eth2 Lodestar Typescript invite docs Eth1 + Eth2 Nimbus eth2 and eth1 Nim invite docs Eth2 Teku (Artemis + Harmony) Java / Kotlin invite docs Eth1 Go-ethereum Go invite docs Eth1 Nethermind C# invite docs Eth1 Besu Java invite docs Eth1 ethereum-JS Javascript invite docs Eth1 Erigon Go Invite-only docs</description></item><item><title>L1 specifications</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l1-specifications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/core-development/l1-specifications/</guid><description>Consensus layer # Consensus specs Beacon APIs, also see interactive site Annotated specs by Vitalik Buterin Eth2 book: extended annotated specs with some eth2 history, by Ben Edgington Legacy (but good) resources: Proof Of Stake F.A.Q. Sharding F.A.Q. Ethereum sharding research compendium Execution layer # Ethereum Improvement Proposals: EIPs Execution APIs New Execution py-specs</description></item></channel></rss>