<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Back end development on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/</link><description>Recent content in Back end development on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/introduction/</guid><description>As far as blockchain development goes, most of the logic that traditional applications would consider backend is encapsulated within smart contracts, however, there are also complementary technologies that allow you to query data from blockchains, index the data, create databases so that you have on-demand data from custom APIs, decentralized storage for content, user authentication / DID, etc. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider this its own specialization, but it is a sufficiently unique skill set for me to cover it separately.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized file storage</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/file-storage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/file-storage/</guid><description>There are many applications that require storing files of all sorts and making them available for your decentralized applications, NFTS for example only have a link to the URI metadata on-chain, and that URI points to a decentralized storage endpoint on IPFS or Arweave. Meaning that all the images and the traits of the NFT are hosted in their file storage networks rather than on the Ethereum mainnet in order to save on costs and allow for higher bandwidth.</description></item><item><title>Indexing / Querying</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/indexing-querying/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/indexing-querying/</guid><description>The applications you will be building need to know what is the state of the blockchain so that your users know what is happening and can interact with the application effectively. An example of this is Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s AMM. In order to call the swap function in the smart contracts, you need to know how many tokens you will get back with an X amount of ETH that you put into the contract.</description></item><item><title>Oracles</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/oracles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/oracles/</guid><description>Oracles are data feeds that bring off-chain data on-chain so that the smart contracts that you build can query real-world information and build logic around it. For example, prediction market Dapps use oracles to settle payments based on events. A prediction market may ask you to bet your ETH on who will become the next president of the United States. They&amp;rsquo;ll use an oracle to confirm the outcome and payout to the winners.</description></item><item><title>DID</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/did/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/did/</guid><description>DID (decentralized identity) and web3 user authentication are a disruptive new primitive on the internet as we can be self-sovereign users of the internet and own our own value within it for the first time in human history. Usually, your user profile is managed by centralized service providers like Google, Facebook, Apple, Amazon, and others. In web3, the concept of a digital identity is much broader as it can span many more different areas such as financial history, games, social interaction (decentralized social media, i.</description></item><item><title>Automation</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/automation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/automation/</guid><description>Within blockchain applications there are many actions that are repetitive and cumbersome to execute, for example, having to change the liquidity provision ranges inside of an active Uniswap v3 liquidity provision strategy, claiming rewards from yield vaults, and many other actions that users would like to automate so as to not have to deal with manual execution overhead.
Gelato network # Gelato Network is an automation protocol that runs as a decentralized network of bots used by web3 developers to automate smart contract executions on public EVM compatible blockchains including Ethereum, Polygon, Fantom, Arbitrum, Binance Smart Chain, and Avalanche.</description></item><item><title>Miscellaneous APIs</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/apis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/back-end-development/apis/</guid><description>When building applications you will want to display miscellaneous information from various different other applications or protocols, e.g. price feeds for different tokens on different AMMs, the price of NFTs listed on different marketplaces, various data from services your application relies on, etc. As a backend developer, your responsibilities are to know where you can find reliable sources of data for your application and build the infrastructure needed to fetch it so that frontend developers can display it on the site.</description></item></channel></rss>