<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Support this guide on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/</link><description>Recent content in Support this guide on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Donations</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/donate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/donate/</guid><description>I’m trying to gather resources to fund the development of this public good blockchain development guide and so I got my fren Ana Rueda (@ruedart) to create this amazing graphic for the Mirror NFT edition. The funds will go to the continued development of this guide (90%) and to Ana for the creation of the art (10%). I’m open to discussion on how to structure the open collaboration around the guide and to allocating the funds into a community-owned multi-sig.</description></item><item><title>Contributions</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/contribute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/support/contribute/</guid><description>If you want to contribute, please join this Telegram group that I created for collaborators so that we can better coordinate and distribute tasks. Eventually we will migrate to a more suitable Discord/Forum setup.
The process to contribute is as follows:
Consult about contribution on Telegram group Submit issue on the main repo with what needs to be done Fork the repo Create a branch with a descriptive name Write contributions Create pull request to main repo with given branch and reference the issue in the PR message and who has worked on it (for more people if applicable).</description></item></channel></rss>