<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Foreword</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/foreword/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/foreword/</guid><description>Nowadays there are countless well-made resources on how to learn blockchain development of all kinds and with different specializations in mind, however, it is still very hard to get guidance and personalized suggestions based on your interests. I am writing this guide in order to provide an aggregator of all the resources that I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years, plus give some opinionated commentary on how to approach them and how to use them in order to maximize learning and practical understanding in order to get building cool things in the space as soon as possible.</description></item><item><title>What is blockchain development?</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/blockchain-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/blockchain-development/</guid><description>There are two main categories in my mind, either you build the infrastructure that runs blockchain-based networks or you build applications that run on top of these decentralized and permissionless networks. Of course, this differentiation doesn&amp;rsquo;t encompass all types of development on blockchains, but it is a good way to get started.
By blockchain infrastructure, people usually mean client implementations of blockchain protocols that nodes or validators run to keep the chains running.</description></item><item><title>Specializations</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/specializations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/specializations/</guid><description>There are many different specializations within blockchain development, each requires a different set of skills, however a general understanding of distributed systems, basic cryptography, and knowing how smart contracts operate is required as a foundation for all of them. In this guide I&amp;rsquo;ll try to provide a general overview of each of them as well as give the best guidance I can provide on the resources learners should prioritize and in which order they should take them.</description></item><item><title>Skill-based specializations</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/skill-based/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/skill-based/</guid><description>There are different sets of skills required for different specializations, the technology stack and knowledge needed are determined by the layer and application that you want to target as a developer. I believe that everyone should get a solid general foundation and try out different areas and niches before settling on the main stack they want to focus on. Some people choose specializations according to the end goal that they want to accomplish using blockchain-based technologies, others like myself feel like everything is interesting and can&amp;rsquo;t settle on a single one to specialize in when confronted with an analysis paralysis situation.</description></item><item><title>Application-based specializations</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/application-based/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/introduction/application-based/</guid><description>Another way to separate types of blockchain development is not based on the underlying tech stack, but on the use case that you are targeting. These are the categories that I believe are the most popular, however, there are many others that I&amp;rsquo;m not covering to keep the scope of this article more manageable.
Coming soon # DeFi Creator Economy MEV L2s Infrastructure Gaming Privacy Coordination / Public goods</description></item></channel></rss>