<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Full-stack development on</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/</link><description>Recent content in Full-stack development on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/introduction/</guid><description>As the name implies, full-stack blockchain development is the closest specialization to being a jack of all trades. It involves building out all of the aspects of an application from front end, to smart contracts, to backend (at least to a certain degree). This is the most generic role that most blockchain developers will take and most companies and DAOs are looking for in a contributor. Since there is such a high demand for quality developers in the space, it is oftentimes the case that employers onboard people from different fields and turn them into a jack of all trades within web3 development so as to save costs and reduce HR resource requirements (which are incredibly scarce nowadays).</description></item><item><title>Full-stack guides</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/guides/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/guides/</guid><description>Guides that will help you become a full-stack blockchain developer:
Open-source Computer Science Introduction to Ethereum Development - Austin Griffith The Complete Guide to Full Stack Web3 Development - Nader Dabit Speed Run Ethereum - Austin Griffith Solidity, Blockchain, and Smart Contracts Course - Beginner to Expert Python Tutorial - Patrick Collins Full-stack blockchain solidity course - Patrick Collins DeFi Developer Roadmap</description></item><item><title>Full-stack tutorials</title><link>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/tutorials/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.devpill.me/docs/full-stack-development/tutorials/</guid><description>Tutorials that are related to full-stack blockchain development:
Introduction to Ethereum Build Uniswap Blockchain Web3 App with Solidity | Next.js | Sanity.io</description></item></channel></rss>